

I am a solutions-oriented developer with a passion for great user experience. I believe technology should be enjoyable and easy to use! While I excel at solving problems on my own, I am most fulfilled when collaborating with others to find solutions.

# CONTACT INFORMATION:

Email: Cathy347Le@gmail.com

Portfolio: https://cathy347le.github.io/ Github: https://github.com/Cathy347Le

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/cathyxle/

Location: Washington, DC Phone: (408) 390-5534

# WORK:

#### **GMMB**

Website with parallax, animations, and hover effects

## Lunar New Year Jeopardy

Self-scoring trivia game utilizing JavaScript, DOM Manipulation, HTML, and CSS

#### Think Movie

Web app to store personalized movie lists. Built with MongoDB, Express, Handlebars, and Node.js.

#### Petz

Social media web app for pets. Users can create a profile for their pets, post comments, and "lick" other pet profiles. Built with React, MongoDB, Express, and Node.js.

## 2018 Senate Elections Map

Recreating the election map using D3.js and React

# FRONT END SKILLS:

- HTML, CSS, Sass
- ¡Query, JavaScript, React
- Grunt, Bootstrap, Materialize

# BACK END SKILLS:

- PHP, Wordpress
- Node, Express
- MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL
- RESTful API

# ADDITIONAL SKILLS.

- Version Control (Git/Github)
- SourceTree, Codeship
- Responsive Web Design
- MVC Methodology
- Accessibility (WCAG)
- Asana, Slack

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

## SOCIAL DRIVER

Maintenance Developer | April 2021 - July 2021 Web Developer | July 2020 - April 2021 Jr Web Developer | July 2019 - July 2020

- Worked with a team of strategists, UX developers, project managers and visual designers to develop and launch over 18 websites using Wordpress, PHP, HTML, Sass, and JavaScript
- Wrote scripts to clean and migrate the data from client's old Wordpress site to redesigned Wordpress site
- Structured backend using PHP and Javascript to setup custom post types, input fields, and taxonomies
- Implemented custom user-friendly front-end components to empower clients to built their own page content
- Created asset boards, documentation, and conducted CMS trainings for clients to ensure the best user experience
- Maintained websites by fixing bugs, optimizing images, updating plugins and code to improve accessibility, responsiveness, and cross browser performance while providing a friendly customer service attitude towards clients

# GENERAL ASSEMBLY (GA) Software Engineering Immersive | Jan 2019 - April 2019

• Three-month full stack development program focused on common best practices in OOP and MVC frameworks.

# **GREENBERG QUINLAN ROSNER**

Research Data Analyst | May 2018 - Jan 2019 Lead Research Data Associate | Jan 2016 - May 2018 Research Data Associate | Nov 2013 -Dec 2015

- Designed and conducted public opinion research, supervised survey fielding, and programmed over 120 political surveys
- Advised analysts and calling house vendors on best practices to achieve accurate, quality survey data

### THE FELDMAN GROUP

Data Specialist | March 2013 - Oct 2013 Research Assistant | Oct 2011 - Feb 2013

Reviewed, programmed, tested, and monitored over 50 political surveys to ensure accuracy and quality

# EDUCATION:

### **GENERAL ASSEMBLY (GA)**

Software Engineering Immersive | Jan 2019 - April 2019

#### **UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA: SAN DIEGO**

B.A Political Science/American Politics | Class of 2010